MIAOSHIQI LIU

Downtown Toronto, Canada

miaoshiqi.liu@mail.utoronto.ca, miaoshiqiliu@gmail.com

http://shiqi.writingspace.cc

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Miaoshiqi LIU is a Ph.D. candidate in the Department of Statistical Sciences at the University of Toronto. In 2019, she earned a bachelor's degree in Mathematics from Tsinghua University, Beijing, China. Her research interests include Mathematical Statistics, Nonparametric Estimation, and Nonstationary Time Series Analysis.

EDUCATION

09/2019 – 07/2024 **Ph.D.**: Statistical Sciences

(Expected) University of Toronto - Toronto, Canada

08/2015 – 07/2019 Bachelor of Science: Mathematical Sciences

Tsinghua University - Beijing, China

• GRE: Verbal 159/170, Quantitative 170/170, Analytical Writing 4.5/6

• TOEFL iBT: 108/120 (R28, L26, S27, W27)

RESEARCH HISTORY

08/2020 - now

Simultaneous Nonparametric Inference Under Complex Temporal Dynamics

(In progress)

Instructor: Zhou Zhou

University of Toronto - Toronto, Canada

- A unified framework on how to conduct a large class of hypothesis testing on varying coefficient model with time-varying nonstationary covariates and error process
- Techniques: Bahadur Representation, Gaussian Approximation, Multiplier Bootstrap

01/2021 - 06/2021

Seminar Project

Instructor: Michael Evans

University of Toronto - Toronto, Canada

• Seminar work on constructing reasonable plausible regions based on relative belief inference

02/2019 - 06/2019

Undergraduate Thesis

Instructor: Lijian Yang, Ying Yang Tsinghua University – Beijing, China

• Literature review thesis on varying coefficient model for gene-environment interaction

07/2018 - 09/2018

Summer Intern

Instructor: Xuming He, Yang Chen

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor – Ann Arbor, Michigan

- A causal-inference project investigating the association between ICU patients' social visits and survival, based on information extracted from nurses' notes
- Techniques: Natural Language Processing, Logit Regression, Propensity Score Matching

PUBLICATIONS AND PREPRINTS

Evans, Michael, Miaoshiqi Liu, Michael Moon, Sabrina Sixta, Siyi Wei, and Siyue Yang. "On some problems of confidence region construction." *arXiv preprint arXiv:2109.05332* (2021).

SKILLS ____

- Language: Mandarin (native), English (fluent), Japanese (Intermediate)
- Programming: R, Matlab, C++, SQL, Python, LaTeX

HOBBIES _____

- Singing (being an Alto in Tsinghua Chorus)
- Table Tennis
- Cooking